Karl Marx / Friedrich Engels Papers ARCH.00860
International Institute of Social History
- B. Exzerpte von Karl Marx (B 1-168)
  - [Heft LVII], X.-XI.1851, englisch, franz., deutsch., B_52; 42 S
    S. 4-5: Gustav Julius, Bankwesen. Ein neues Gespenst in Deutschland, 1846
    S. 6-7: Charles Coquelin, Du crédit et des banques dans l'industrie, in: Revue des Deux Mondes, 1842
    S. 7-8: J. Faucher, In der Bankfrage gegen Gustav Julius, 1846
    S. 8-9: F. Vidal, De la répartition des richesses..., 1846
    S. 9-10 u. 32-34: Daniel Hardcastle, Banks und bankers, 1843
    S. 11-14 u. 17-23: Thomas Corbet, An inquiry into the causes and modes of the wealth of individuals..., 1841
    S. 15-16 u. 35-40: A. Quetelet, A treatise on man and the development of his faculties, 1842
    S. 24-31: Frédéric Bastiat u. Pierre-Joseph Proudhon, Gratuité du Crédit(Diskussion), 1850
    S. 31: Berechnungen zu Bastiat
    S. 34: Eugène Forcade, [Über Proudhon], in: Revue des Deux Mondes, 1848
    S. 40-42: Samuel P. Newman, Elements of political economy, 1835.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 57.
  - [Heft LIV], VII./VIII.1851 oder Ende 1851, deutsch, englisch, italienisch, lateinisch., B_53; 60 S
    S. 1-2: K.D. Hüllmann, Städtewesen des Mittelalters, 1826-1829
    S. 2-6: F. De Forbonnais, Recherches et considérations sur les finances de France, 1784
    S. 7-29: Simonde de Sismondi, Historical view of the literature of the south of Europe, 1846
    auf S. 14-15, 16-17, 19-20: Bibliogr. u. kleine Exzerpte von Italienischer Literatur
    S. 30-33, 37-41 u. 42-60: Fr. Bouterwek, Geschichte der Poesie und Beredsamkeit, 1801-1812
    S. 34: Jordano Bruno, Candelajo, 1582
    S. 34: ders., De triplici minimo et mensura..., 1591
    S. 34-35: ders., De la causa, principio, et uno, 1584
    S. 41/42: Bibliogr. von Bruno.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 54.
  - [Heft XLIV], ca. III.1851, deutsch, franz., B_54; 81 S
    S. 1-2: G.W. Gilbart, An inquiry into the causes of the pressure on the moneymarket..., 1840
    S. 2-3: E. Thornton, Observations on the report..., 1811
    S. 3-5: Albert Gallatin, Considerations on the currency and banking system of the United States, 1831
    S. 6-8: James W. Gilbart, The history of banking in America, [1837]
    S. 8-9: ders., The history of banking in Ireland, 1836
    S. 9: Samuel Bailey, A defense of joint stock banks..., 1840
    S. 10-15, 17-22: C. Raguet, A treatise on Currency and Banking, 1840
    S. 16-17: Tr. Twiss, View of the progress of political economy, 1844
    S. 22-27: The currency question reviewed..., 1845
    S. 27-29: J.W. Bosanquet, Metallic, paper and credit currency, 1842
    S. 29-31: Report... from the select Committee... into the cause of the high price of gold bullion, 1810
    S. 32-33: Charles Bosanquet, Practical observations on the report of the Bullion-Committee, 1810
    S. 33-35: David Ricardo, The high price of bullion..., 1811
    S. 35-36: ders., Reply to Mr. Bosanquets practical observations, 1811
    S. 36-42: Thomas Tooke, An inquiry into the currency principle, 1844
    S. 42-44: R. Torrens, On the operation of the Bank Charter Act of 1844..., 1847
    S. 44-47: John G. Hubbard, The currency and the country..., 1843
    S. 47-48: William Leatham, Letters on the currency..., 1840
    S. 48-52: Marx, fragment. Konzept über das Geld ("Die Unterscheidung des Handels...")
    S. 52-58: Reports... from Committees of the House, 1810
    S. 58-72: Reports from Committees. Commercial distress, 1847-1848, Vol. II, Pt. I
    S. 72-81: Adam Smith, An inquiry into the nature and causes of the wealth of nations, ed. MacCulloch, 1828.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 44.
  - [Heft XLV], ca. V.1851, englisch, deutsch, italienisch., B_55; 88 S
    S. 1: Adam Smith, An inquiry into the nature and causes of the wealth of nations, ed. MacCulloch, 1828
    S. 1-2: G. Ustariz, The theory and practice of Commerce, 1751
    S. 2-7 u. 66-67: The Economist, Jg. 1845
    S. 7-11: John Morton, On the nature and property of soils, 1838
    S. 7, 11-18, 22-28, 41-42, 52, 54-55, 68-77: James Steuart, An inquiry into the principles of political economy, 1770
    S. 19-21, 29-40, 43-49, 53, 56-65: David Ricardo, On the principles of political economy, 1821
    S. 50-51: Antonio Serra, Breve trattato della cause che possono far abbondare li Regni d'oro e d'argento..., 1803
    S. 77-78: G. Montari, Della Moneta. Trattato mercantile, ed. 1804
    S. 78-79: R. Torrens, An essay on money and paper currency, 1812
    S. 80-83: William M. Gouge, A short history of paper money..., 1833
    S. 83-88: W. Cooke Taylor, The natural history of society..., 1840.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 45.
  - [Heft XLVI], ca. II.1851, englisch, deutsch., B_56; 74 S
    S. 1-8: The Economist, Jg. 1847
    S. 8-18: The Economist, Jg. 1844
    S. 18-20: David Hume, Essays and treatises on several subjects, 1777
    S. 20-24: John Locke, Some considerations on the consequences of the lowering of interest, in: Works, II, 1768
    S. 24-32: Henry Thornton, An enquiry into the nature... of paper credit, 1802
    S. 33-36: Th. Mortimer, Every man his own broker..., 1782
    S. 36: Robert Hamilton, An inquiry concerning... the national debt..., 1814
    S. 37: William Cobbet, Manchester lectures in support of his fourteen reform propositions..., 1832
    S. 37-39, 53-57 u. 62-63: John Francis, History of the Bank of England, 1848
    S. 39-41: Th. Joplin, Currency reform: improvement not depreciation, 1844
    S. 41-42: The currency question; currency records... 1819 and 1844, 1847
    S. 42-49: John Gray, Lectures on the nature... of money, 1848
    S. 49-53: P.J. Stirling, The philosophy of trade..., 1846
    S. 57-59: G.M. Bell, The philosophy of join stock banking, 1840
    S. 60-62: ders., The currency question..., 1841
    S. 63-65: John G. Kinnaer, The crisis and the currency..., 1847
    S. 65-66 u. 68-73: G.M. Bell, The country banks and the currency, 1842
    S. 67-68: The city, or the physiology of London business..., 1845
    S. 73-74:... mond(?), Causes which lead to a Bank Restriction Bill, 1839
    S. 74: The Economist, 1.I.-15.II.1851.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 46.
  - [Heft LI], 1851, englisch, deutsch., B_57; 42 S
    S. 1-3: George Ramsay, An essay on the distribution of wealth, 1836
    S. 4-5: Thomas de Quincey, The logic of political economy, 1845
    S. 5-11: H.C. Carey, Essay on the rate of wages,..., 1835
    S. 10: Dialogues of three Templars on political economy... ( London Magazine, 1824)
    S. 12-36: H.C. Carey, Principles of political economy, I u. II, 1837-1838
    S. 36-41: ders., The past, the present and the future, 1848
    S. 41-42: T.R. Malthus, Principles of political economy..., 1836.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 51.
  - [Heft LII], 1851, englisch, deutsch., B_58; 90 S
    S. 1: W.A. Mackinnon, History of civilisation, 1846
    S. 2-20, 34-39 u. 65: J.D. Tuckett, A history of the past and present state of the labouring population, 1846
    S. 21-23: John Barton, Observations on... the condition of the labouring classes of society, 1817
    S. 23-24: The Westminster Review, I.1826
    S. 24-28: David Buchanan, Observations on the subjects treated of in Dr. Smith's Inquiry..., 1814
    S. 29-30: T.R. Malthus, The measure of value stated and illustrated, 1823
    S. 30-32: R. Torrens, An essay on the production of wealth, 1821
    S. 32-33 u. 40-41: Piercy(?) Ravenstone, Thoughts on the funding system and its effects, 1824
    S. 41-47: Thomas Hodgskin, Popular political economy, 1827
    S. 47-49: Richard Jones, An introductory lecture on political economy, 1833
    S. 49-51: T.R. Malthus, Definitions in political economy, 1827
    S. 52-60: Thomas Chalmers, On political economy in connection with the moral state and moral prospects of society, 1832
    S. 60-61: Edinburgh Review, 1837 (Rez. über Chalmers' Buch)
    S. 62-64: G. Poulett Scrope, Principles of political economy, 1833
    S. 66-68 u. 70-71: W. Blake, Observations on the effects produced by the expenditure of government..., 1823
    S. 69: John R. MacCulloch, The litterature of political economy, 1845
    S. 71: Edinburgh Review, Vol. CIV, Art. IV (Jones on the theory of rent)
    S. 71-83: Richard Jones, An essay on the distribution of wealth..., 1831
    S. 83: Thomas Sharpe Smith, On the economy of nations, 1842
    S. 83-90: George Ramsay, An essay on the distribution of wealth, 1836
    S. 86: Richard Whately, Introductory lectures on political economy, 1847.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 52.
  - [Heft LIII], 1851, deutsch, englisch., B_59; 58 S
    S. 1-7: Justus Liebig, Die organische Chemie in ihrer Anwendung auf Agricultur und Physiologie, 1842
    S. 7: J.C. London, An Encyclopedia of agriculture..., 1831
    S. 8-9: Joseph Townsend, A dissertation on the Poor Laws, 1817
    S. 9: ders., A journey through Spain..., 1791
    S. 10: Wallace, A dissertation on the number of mankind..., 1753
    S. 11: David Hume, Political Discourses, 1752
    S. 11-13: T.R. Malthus, An essay on the principle of population, 1798
    S. 13-14: George Purves, Gray versus Malthus, the principle of population, 1818
    S. 14-21: W. Thomas Thornton, Overpopulation and its remedy, 1846
    S. 21: Robert Vaughan, The age of great cities, 1843
    S. 21-23: Thomas Doubleday, The true law of population, 1842
    S. 23: W.P. Alison, Observations on the management of the poor in Scotland, 1840
    S. 24-34 u. 55-56: Archibald Alison, The principles of population, 1840
    S. 34-55: J.F.W. Johnston, Lectures on agricultural chemistry and geology, 1847
    S. 57-58: The Economist, 28.VI.-5.VII.1851.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 53.
  - [Heft XLVIII], XI.1851-VII.1852, englisch, deutsch., B_60; 64 S
    S. 1-7: The Economist, 23.VIII.-8.XI.1851
    S. 8: Samuel P. Newman, Elements of political economy, 1835
    S. 8: Francis W. Newman, Four lectures on the contrast of ancient and modern history, 1847
    S. 8-9: John Gray, The social system, 1831
    S. 10-13 u. 31: Henry Hallam, View of the state of Europe..., 1846
    S. 14-18: K.D. Hüllmann, Geschichte des Ursprungs der Stände in Deutschland, 1830
    S. 18-21: ders., Geschichte des Ursprungs der Deutschen Fürstenwürde, 1842
    S. 21-26: ders., Deutsche Finanzgeschichte des Mittelalters, 1805
    S. 26-31: J. Dalrymple, An essay towards a general history of feudal property in Great Britain, 1759
    S. 32-64: K.D. Hüllmann, Städtewesen des Mittelalters, 1826-1829.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 48.
  - [Heft LIX], VIII.1852, franz., deutsch., B_61; 57 S
    S. 3-5: Johann Gottfried Eichhorn, Allgemeine Geschichte der Cultur und Litteratur..., 1796
    S. 6-16: John Millar, Observations concerning the distribution of ranks in society, 1773
    S. 16: G. Jung, Geschichte der Frauen, 1850
    S. 17: J.A. de Ségur, Les femmes, leur condition et leur influence dans l'ordre social, 1803
    S. 18-30, 43-48 u. 54-56: Wilhelm Wachsmuth, Allgemeine Culturgeschichte, 1850-1851
    S. 31-43: Christophn Meiners, Geschichte des weiblichen Geschlechts, 1788-1800
    S. 49-50: Thomas, Essai sur le caractère, les moeurs et l'esprit des femmes, 1773
    S. 50-51: William Alexander, The history of women..., 1782
    S. 52-54: W. Drumann, Grundriss der Culturgeschichte, 1847
    S. 57: Militärische Biblogr.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 59.
  - [Heft LX], X.1852, deutsch, englisch., B_62; 80 S
    S. 2: Inhaltsverzeichnis u. Notiz
    S. 3-40 u. 47-51: Wilhelm Wachsmuth, Allgemeine Culturgeschichte, 1850-1851
    S. 41: Charles Knight, Capital and labour, including the results of machinery, 1845
    S. 41-46: Ferdinando Galiani, Della moneta, ed. 1803
    S. 51-53: Roman St. Kaulfuss, Die Slawen in den ältesten Zeiten bis Samo, 1842
    S. 53-77: Wilhelm Wachsmuth, Europäische Sittengeschichte, 1830-1833
    S. 78: Notiz: "Englische Kings und Queens"
    S. 79-80: Notizen.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 60.
  - [Heft LXIV], ab I.1853, englisch, deutsch, franz., B_63; 65 S
    S. 1-7: Herbert Spencer, A theory of population..., 1852
    S. 7-16: George Opdyke, A treatise on political economy, 1851
    S. 16-22: Francis W. Newman, Lectures on political economy, 1851
    S. 22-27: Thomas C. Banfield, The organisation of industry..., 1848
    S. 28: Thomas C. Banfield u. R.C. Weld, The statistical companion, 1848
    S. 29-33: Herbert Spencer, Social statistics..., 1851
    S. 33: Notiz über House of Commons-Debat über Reform Bill, 1831
    S. 34-43: Wilhelm Wachsmuth, Europäische Sittengeschichte, 1831-1833
    S. 44: Bibliogr. Notizen
    S. 44-45: John R. MacCulloch, Litterature of political economy, 1845
    S. 45-46: Gustav Klein, Allgemeine Kulturgeschichte, Bde VI u. VII, 1847-1849
    S. 47-48: Indian railways and their probable results..., 1848
    S. 49: Prince Saltykow, Lettres sur l'Inde, 1849
    S. 49-52 u. 57: John R. MacCulloch, Dictionary of... commerce, 1846
    S. 52: India, Great Britain and Russia, 1838
    S. 52-56: Observations on India, By a Resident there..., 1853
    S. 56-58: A.H.L. Heeren, De la politique et du commerce des peuples de l'antiquité, Tome III, 1833
    S. 59-61: The Economist, 22.I.-21.IV.1853
    S. 62: Bibliogr. Notizen über Indien
    S. 62-65: François Bernier, Voyages: contenant la description des étas du Grand Mogul..., 1830.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 64.
  - [Heft LXV], VI.1853, englisch., B_64; 12 S
    NB. Schriften, publ. durch d. India Reform Association.
    S. 1-2 no.I: The Government of India since 1834, 1853
    S. 2-4 no.II: The Finances of India, 1853
    S. 4-6 no.III: Notes on India by Dr. Buist of Bombay, 1853
    S. 6-8 no.IV: John Sullivan, Extract from Mill's History on the double government..., 1853
    S. 8-11 no.V: John Dickinson, The government of India, 1853
    S. 11 no.VI: The Native States of India, 1853
    S. 11-12 no.VII: India wrongs without a remedy, 1853
    S. 12: Bleistiftnotizen für NYDT-Artikel, 6.V.1854.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 65.
  - [Heft LXVI], VI.1853, englisch u. deutsch., B_65; 52 S
    S. 2: Inhalt
    S. 3-7: Thomas St. Raffles, The history of Java, 1817
    S. 7-9: Mark Wilks, Historical sketches of the South of India..., 1810-1817
    S. 9: J.F. Royle, Essay on the productive resources of India, 1840
    S. 9: An inquiry into the causes of the long continued stationary condition of India..., 1830
    S. 9-12: Hugh Murray u.a., Historical and descriptive account of British India..., 1832
    S. 12-22 u. 24-32: George Campbell, Modern India, 1852
    S. 23: ders., A scheme for the government of India, 1853
    S. 23-24: John Chapman, The cotton and commerce of India..., 1851
    S. 32 u. 37-39: Robert Patton, The principles of Asiatic monarchies..., 1801
    S. 33-37: The Portfolio - or a collection of state papers..., Vol. I, 1843
    S. 40: Classified index to the London Catalogues, 1853
    S. 41-42: J.Ph. Fallmerayer, Fragmente aus dem Orient, 1845
    S. 43-44: Ersch u. Gruber, Dänemark
    S. 43: Demographische Notiz über Dänemark
    S. 44-47: Historische Übersicht über die schlesw.-holsteinischen Bewegungen
    S. 47-48: C.F. Wegener, Über das wahre Verhältnis des Herzogs von Augustenburg, 1849
    S. 49-50: J.G. Droysen u. H. Samwer, Die Herzogthümer Schleswig-Holstein und das Königreich Dänemark, 1850
    S. 50-52: Theodor Olshausen, Das Dänische Königsgesetz, 1838.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 66.
  - [Heft LXI], 1853, deutsch, englisch., B_66; 27 S
    S. 1-12: Wilhelm Wachsmuth, Europäische Sittengeschichte, 1831-1833
    S. 13-27: House of Commons, Debatte über Russland, 1831-1848.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 61.
  - [Heft LXIII], 1853, englisch, deutsch., B_67; 84 S
    S. 1-4: The Russians in Moldavia and Wallachia, 1849
    S. 4-5: Russlands Politik und Heere in den letzten Jahren, 1852
    S. 5-13: The Greek and Eastern Churches..., 1852
    S. 13-14: J.M. Neale, Introduction to the history of the Holy Eastern Church, Appendix, 1851
    S. 14 u. 18-19: Valerian Krasinski, Sketch of the religious history of the slavonic nations, 1851
    S. 15-17: Die Staatskirche Russlands im Jahre 1839, 1844
    S. 18: Traité, conclu près du village de Koutschoui Kaynardji(?), d.d. 10 juillet 1774
    S. 20-24, 33-35, 37-46, 79-84: Houses of Commons and Lordsüber Russland, 1833-1841
    S. 58-63, 24-28 u. 36: Georg Friedrich von Martens, Grundriss einer diplomatischen Geschichte..., 1807
    S. 47-57 u. 29-32: David Urquhart, Progress of Russia in the West, North and South, 1853
    S. 64-79: G.K. Francis, Opinions and policy of... Palmerston, 1852.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 63.
  - [Heft LXXVI], nach 1853, englisch u. deutsch., B_68; 68 S
    S. 1-37: Correspondance relative to the affairs of the Levant, 1841
    S. 38-58 u. 64-67: G.F. Martens, Grundriss einer diplomatischen Geschichte..., 1807
    S. 59-63: D. Urquhart, Portfolio, Vol. II, 1843-1844
    S. 67-68: Pierre Joubert, Histoire des révolutions de Pologne, 1775 [? - u.U. nur bibliogr. Notiz aus Martens!].
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 76.
  - [Heft LXVII], 1853-1854, englisch u. franz., B_69; 26 S
    S. 2: Buchtitel u. Notizen über englische idiomatische Formen
    S. 3: Letter from Robert Monteith to William Brown: Reasons for demanding Investigation..., 1840
    S. 3-4: William Cargyll, Address to the South Shield Chamber of Commerce... on the foreign policy..., 1840
    S. 4: David Urquhart, La crise, 1840
    S. 5: ders., An appeal against faction, 1843
    S. 5-10: The Portfolio - or a collection of state papers 1836-37; 1843 (cont.)
    S. 11-21: César Famin, Histoire de la rivalité et du protectorat des églises chrétiens..., 1853
    S. 22: Ms.-Entwurf über Russisch-Türkischen Krieg, NYDT, 19.VII.1854
    S. 23-25: Notizen zur Phonetik (Fragm.)
    S. 26: Notiz.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 67.
  - [Heft LXVIII], 1854, englisch, spanisch, franz., B_70; 78 S
    S. 2-10: Henry Headley Parish, The diplomatic history of the monarchy of Greece..., 1838
    S. 11: Bibliogr. Notizen
    S. 11: Una Plumada sobre la indola y tendencia de revolucion en Espana, 1846
    S. 11-13 u. 37-47: Révolution d'Espagne. Examen critique 1820-1836, 1836
    S. 14-15: Principe, Espartero, su passada, su presente, su porvenir, 1848
    S. 15-19: The crisis of Spain, 1823
    S. 20-37: Revelations of Spain in 1845, 1845
    S. 55-48: M. de Marliani, Historia politica de la Espana moderna, 1849
    S. 64-78, 60-64 u. 60-56: Augustin Thierry, Essai sur l'histoire de la formation et des progrés du Tiers Etat, 1853.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 68.
  - [Heft LXX], VIII.1854, englisch, franz., spanisch., B_71; 46 S
    S. 1-7: The political constitution of the Spanish Monarchy 1813.
    S. 7: Bibliogr. Notiz
    S. 7-19 u. 23-24: Robert Southey, History of the Peninsular War, 1823-1832
    S. 20-22: Alph. Du Casse(ed.), Memoires et correspondance politique et militaire du Roi Joseph Napoleon, 1853
    S. 22: Constitution décrétée par l'assemblée Constituante, 1791
    S. 25-26: John Bigland, Histoire de l'Espagne..., 1823
    S. 26: Bibliogr. Notiz
    S. 26-35: W. Walton, The revolutions of Spain, 1837 (cont.)
    S. 35: M. de Marliani, Historia politica de la Espana moderna, 1849 (cont.)
    S. 35-46: Conde de Toreno, Historia del Levantamiento... de Espana, 1835-1837.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 70.
  - [Heft LXXI], IX(?).1854, englisch, deutsch, franz., spanisch., B_72; 35 S
    S. 1-3: Briefkonzept von Laura Marx
    S. 4-5: Ms. von Marx über die span. Centraljunta
    S. 6-12, 19-24 u. 26-30: Conde de Toreno, Historia del Levantamiento... de Espana, 1835-1837 (cont.)
    S. 14-19: H. von Brandt, The two Alinas and the Spanish guerillas..., 1825
    S. 12-14 u. 25: Abbé D.D. de Pradt, Memoires historiques sur la Révolution de l'Espagne, 1816
    S. 25: ders., De la révolution actuelle de l'Espagne, 1820
    S. 31-35: G. de Jovellanos, Obras, 1839-1840.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 71.
  - [Heft LXIX], X.1854, englisch, franz., spanisch, deutsch., B_73; 46 S
    S. 1-2: G. de Jovellanos, Obras, 1839-1840
    S. 2-4: Henry W. Davids, The war of Ormuzd and Ahriman in the nineteenth century, 1852
    S. 4: Evaristo San Miguel, Memoria sucinta sobre lo acaeido en la Columna movil de las tropas nacionales..., 1820
    S. 4-6: Leucadio Doblado, Letters from Spain, 1822
    S. 6-12: Christopher Clarke, An Examination of the internal state of Spain..., 1818
    S. 12: John Bramsen, Remark on the North of Spain, 1823
    S. 12-17: The last days of Spain, 1823
    S. 17-23: Pedro Urquinaona, La Espana bajo el poder arbitraro de la Congregacion Apostolica..., 1833
    S. 23: Who is the liberator of Spain(transl. H. Wood), 1846
    S. 23-25: The Holy Alliance versus Spain, 1823
    S. 25-30: F.R. Chateaubriand, Congrès de Vérone; Guerre d'Espagne..., 1838
    S. 30-32: Revolution d'Espagne. Examen critique 1820-1836, 1836 (cont.)
    S. 33-34 u. 40: M. de Marliani, Historia politica de la Espana moderna, 1849 (cont.)
    S. 35-37: W. Walton, The revolutions of Spain, 1837 (cont.)
    S. 37-38: Victor Du Hamel, Historia constitucional de la Monarchia Espanola..., 1848
    S. 38-39: Jose M. Calatrava, "Carta del..." beantwortet von A.F. Estrada, 1825
    S. 40-45: Michael J. Quin, A visit to Spain, 1823
    S. 46: Notiz.
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 69.
  - [Heft LXXII], IX.1854-1855, englisch, spanisch u. deutsch., B_74; 41 S
    S. 1: Umschlag mit Datierung
    S. 3-12: Victor de Hamel, Historia constitucional de la Monarquia Espanola..., 1848 (cont.)
    S. 12: Fastos Espanoles o efeménides de la guerra civil desde octobre de 1807, Madrid 1839 (Bibliogr. Notiz u. Bemerkung von Marx)
    S. 12: Abbé D.D. de Pradt, Garanties à demander à l'Espagne, 1827
    S. 12-13: E. San Miguel, De la Guerra Civil de Espana, 1836
    S. 14-15: An historical inquiry into the unchangeable character of a war in Spain, 1837
    S. 15-17: L'Espagne et la crise présente..., 1843
    S. 18-20 u. 23-34: M. de Marliani, Historia politica de la Espana moderna, 1849 (cont.)
    S. 21-23: Michael J. Quin, A visit to Spain, 1823 (cont.)
    S. 34: Bibliogr. Notiz
    S. 35-36: Edinburgh Review, Vol. XXXVIII-XL
    S. 37-38: The Economist, 6.I.1855
    S. 39-41: Ms. fragm. Konzept für NYDT-Artikel [26.I.1855(?)].
    NB. digitalisiert IISG-Original B 72.
  - [Heft LXXIX], 1854-1856, franz., deutsch, englisch., B_75; 43 S
    S. 1: Notiz
    S. 2: Bibliogr. Notizen
    S. 3-5: Ms., Konzept zu einem Artikel über Spanien
    S. 6: Inhaltsverzeichnis
    S. 7-30: Exzerpte aus Exzerpten, enthaltend:
    S. 7: G.W. Gilgart, An inquiry into the causes of the pressure..., 1840
    S. 7: E. Thornton, Observations on the report,..., 1811
    S. 7: Albert Gallatin, Considerations on the currency and banking, 1831
    S. 7-8: Thomas Tooke, An inquiry into the currency principle, 1844
    S. 8: R. Torrens, On the operation of the bank charter..., 1847
    S. 8: William Leatham, Letters on the currency..., 1840
    S. 9: John G. Hubbard, The currency and the country, 1843
    S. 9-10: J.St. Mill, [Value of Money ?]
    S. 10-11: John Fullarton, On the regulation of currencies, 1844 (1.ed.)
    S. 11-13: Thomas Tooke, A history of prices I/II, 1838
    S. 13-14: W. Blake, Observations on the principles..., 1810
    S. 15-16: John Fullarton, On the regulation of currencies, 1845 (2. ed.)
    S. 16-21: The Economist, 1847
    S. 21-22: The principles and practical operations of Sir Robert Peel's act of 1844
    S. 22: Ashburton, Crisis of 1847
    S. 22: Alison, Free trade and a fettered currency(?), 1847(?)
    S. 22: The Economist, 1845
    S. 22: William Petty, Essay concerning the multiplication of mankind, 1698
    S. 22-23: Charles D'Avenant, Discourses on the public revenues I/II, 1698